Michael Fatigati

Profile

I'm a full-stack software engineer and co-creator of Sentinel, an open-source, self-hosted platform as a service (PaaS). I have multiple years of experience in the JavaScript/Node.js and Go ecosystems, and I'm comfortable working with, AWS infrastructure, Docker swarm mode, PostgreSQL, Prometheus, and more. I also have a PhD in Classical Arabic philosophy, and my passion for mastering languages has found a happy home in software.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer & Co-Creator, Sentinel (open-source PaaS) ☑

2022 - present

Allows users to easily deploy multiple database-backed web applications, with built in support for upgrading applications via canary deployments.

- Automated provisioning and configuration of cloud infrastructure using *Terraform* and *Ansible*.
- Implemented a multi-tenant architecture by using *Docker* containers and Docker in *Swarm Mode* for container orchestration.
- Used *Traefik* reverse proxy to implement traffic splitting and sticky sessions for canary deployments.
- Configured monitoring tools (*Prometheus*, *Grafana* and *Node Exporter*) to determine health of canary deployments.
- Contributed to command line interface for user interactions using OCLIF.
- Authored technical case study about Sentinel.

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2019 - 2021

A few of the projects & technologies used during this time:

- Reference Manager: organize references for research papers and generate bibliographies (Go's net/http and html/template libraries, PostgresSQL)
- Hookie: a tool to develop, receive & debug webhooks (TypeScript, Pug, PostgresSQL, MongoDB)
- Mellow: Trello-like collaboration app (Express, React/Redux, MongoDB)

SSHRC Postdoctoral Research Fellow, NYU Abu Dhabi

2021 - 2022

Translation and analysis of Classical Arabic sources

Instructor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

2015 - 2021

Arabic/Islamic thought, Ancient philosophy, Ethics, Literature and Philosophy

Skills

- Languages: JavaScript/Node.js, Go, TypeScript, SQL, HTML/CSS
- Frameworks & Libraries: Express, React/Redux, jQuery, Handlebars, Pug, Jest
- Cloud: AWS (EC2, IAM); Digital Ocean, Heroku
- **Misc. Technologies**: Docker (swarm mode), Ansible, Terraform, Prometheus, Grafana, Traefik, Github, RESTful API, OCLIF, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Education

Software Engineering, Launch School

2019 - 2021

Multi-year, mastery-baed software engineering curriculum, with progression gated by written exams and living coding interviews. Read more here. ☑

PhD, Classical Arabic/Islamic Philosophy, University of Toronto

2021

MA, Greek and Latin Philosophy, Villanova University

2013